<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HIST 8010 Research Skills and Design Tools on Amber R. Edwards</title>
    <link>https://example.com/hist8010/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HIST 8010 Research Skills and Design Tools on Amber R. Edwards</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://example.com/hist8010/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Analysis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/hist8010/analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/hist8010/analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If doing research is a car, analysis is the oil or the gas – you technically have a car without it, but it isn’t really worth anything or useful to take you anywhere. These exercises contributed to the overall ‘professionalization’ goal of this course/program more broadly, and inform how to engage with other historians and scholarship. Without being able to read other analyses with a critical eye, discern fact from argumentation, and – particularly for my aims – consider digital projects and their unique contributions, there isn’t a well rounded goal to working with sources or creating visualizations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sources</title>
      <link>https://example.com/hist8010/sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/hist8010/sources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Regarding sources, we covered how to collect information through note taking, verifying information through citations – and multiple software applications to streamline those processes and make compiling and saving large amounts of data easier and safer. Conceptually, I came into this semester feeling I had a decent handle on what worked for me regarding note taking and research approaches. While that may have been true, what I didn’t realize was the variety of tools available meant explicitly to make my life easier, and the skills required for engaging with sources that I simply had not been exposed to coming from a 2 year break from academia after undergrad.In the following sections, I’ll elaborate on how my practices have changed since making earlier posts, and some reflections on what I find most useful going forward.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visualization</title>
      <link>https://example.com/hist8010/visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/hist8010/visualization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Visualizations, certainly the most entertaining, led to the most thoughtful consideration about where my research interests align with digital work.Having some experience with online exhibits through Omeka, Storymaps, and general presentation experience that pulled in different visualizations adjacent to those we covered, I found myself surprised at the novelty some of the tools’ utility for different projects.While I’ll analyze my usage of these tools from a current perspective, I’m especially interested in reflecting on how I see visualization tools differently from the thought process of looking toward an eventual dissertation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
