<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Amber R. Edwards</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Amber R. Edwards</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/re1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/re1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;&#xA;&lt;html&gt;&#xA;    &lt;head&gt;&#xA;        &lt;title&gt;RE1: Collecting Information&lt;/title&gt;&#xA;        &lt;date&gt;2024-08-29&lt;/date&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/head&gt;&#xA;    &lt;body&gt;&#xA;        &lt;h1&gt;RE1: Collecting Information&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/EllaBaker.png&#34; alt=&#34;image of Ella Baker&#34; style=&#34;width:350px; float:left&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;p&gt;Note taking is one of the most important research tools, and the first step to writing a successful argument for any length of paper. &#xA;            My note taking style revolves around summarizing topics and arguments as well as catching any recurring themes that may be helpful to my research aims. &#xA;            Turabian’s &lt;em&gt;Manual for Writers&lt;/em&gt;breaks down what research is, how we should think of it, and how to conduct it properly in order to best articulate our argument. &#xA;            The topic sentence breakdown of &#34;I am working on X because I want to find out Y, so that I can help others understand Z” is something foundational that is taught in high schools and undergrad, but understanding each element will help you identify topics when reading other historians’ work. &#xA;            Not every source you read will follow that sentence structure, not even close, but in every good argument those three elements should be present in some form. &#xA;            I’ll also highlight any names or works that I recognize to draw connections when I put my notes into Obsidian (a note-taking software). &#xA;            Each book I’ve read has its own page on Obsidian where I keep a quick summary, notes about the author, and tags for each theme to tie the different pages together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/re5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/re5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;&#xA;&lt;html&gt;&#xA;    &lt;head&gt;&#xA;        &lt;title&gt;RE5 - The Impact of the AI Revolution on Information Archives&lt;/title&gt;&#xA;        &lt;date&gt;2024-10-05&lt;/date&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/head&gt;&#xA;    &lt;body&gt;&#xA;        &lt;h1&gt;RE5 - The Impact of the AI Revolution on Information Archives&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/RE5.png&#34; alt=&#34;two women with caption That Woman is Real Competition&#34; style=&#34;width:250px; float:left&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;        &lt;p&gt;This week, in correlation with Clemson’s Humanities in the Machine Symposium, we’re looking at JSTOR’s beta AI tool.&#xA;             The article I chose to analyze is “Sex and the Me Decade: Sex and Dating Advice Literature of the 1970s” by Anna Ward in &lt;em&gt;Women’s Studies Quarterly&lt;/em&gt; in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/re6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/re6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;&#xA;&lt;html&gt;&#xA;    &lt;head&gt;&#xA;        &lt;title&gt;RE6 - Critical Reading(s)&lt;/title&gt;&#xA;        &lt;date&gt;2024-10-09&lt;/date&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/head&gt;&#xA;    &lt;body&gt;&#xA;        &lt;h1&gt;RE6 - Critical Reading(s)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/GreatMeadow.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;cover of The Great Meadow, by Brian Donahue&#34; style=&#34;width:350px; float:left&#34;&gt;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;This week we’re looking at reviews, for which I chose a book for my Spatial History class, The Great Meadow: Farmers and the Land in Colonial Concord.&#xA;                 Having already reviewed this work in contrast with corresponding articles and digital projects, I was curious to see what other thought of it closer to the time it came out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
